<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<billStatus>
  <bill>
    <calendarNumbers />
    <congress>115</congress>
    <titles>
      <item>
        <title>Recreation Not Red-Tape Act</title>
        <titleType>Short Titles as Introduced</titleType>
        <parentTitleType />
        <chamberCode />
        <chamberName />
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>A bill to promote innovative approaches to outdoor recreation on Federal land and to open up opportunities for collaboration with non-Federal partners, and for other purposes.</title>
        <titleType>Official Title as Introduced</titleType>
        <parentTitleType />
        <chamberCode />
        <chamberName />
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Recreation Not Red-Tape Act</title>
        <titleType>Display Title</titleType>
        <parentTitleType />
        <chamberCode />
        <chamberName />
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Recreation Not Red-Tape Act</title>
        <titleType>(Extracted from GPO) Short Titles as Introduced</titleType>
        <parentTitleType />
        <chamberCode />
        <chamberName />
      </item>
    </titles>
    <introducedDate>2017-07-26</introducedDate>
    <latestAction>
      <actionDate>2017-07-26</actionDate>
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources.</text>
      <links />
    </latestAction>
    <title>Recreation Not Red-Tape Act</title>
    <subjects>
      <billSubjects>
        <policyArea>
          <name>Public Lands and Natural Resources</name>
        </policyArea>
        <legislativeSubjects />
      </billSubjects>
    </subjects>
    <relatedBills>
      <item>
        <congress>115</congress>
        <number>3400</number>
        <type>HR</type>
        <relationshipDetails>
          <item>
            <type>Identical bill</type>
            <identifiedBy>CRS</identifiedBy>
          </item>
        </relationshipDetails>
        <latestTitle>Recreation Not Red-Tape Act</latestTitle>
        <latestAction>
          <text>Subcommittee Hearings Held.</text>
          <actionDate>2017-10-03</actionDate>
        </latestAction>
      </item>
    </relatedBills>
    <updateDate>2018-02-06T16:45:41Z</updateDate>
    <committeeReports />
    <notes />
    <recordedVotes />
    <amendments />
    <createDate>2017-07-27T00:41:33Z</createDate>
    <committees>
      <billCommittees>
        <item>
          <systemCode>sseg00</systemCode>
          <chamber>Senate</chamber>
          <type>Standing</type>
          <activities>
            <item>
              <date>2017-07-26T18:20:54Z</date>
              <name>Referred to</name>
            </item>
          </activities>
          <name>Energy and Natural Resources Committee</name>
          <subcommittees />
        </item>
      </billCommittees>
    </committees>
    <cboCostEstimates />
    <billNumber>1633</billNumber>
    <policyArea>
      <name>Public Lands and Natural Resources</name>
    </policyArea>
    <version>1.0.0</version>
    <billType>S</billType>
    <originChamber>Senate</originChamber>
    <actions>
      <item>
        <actionDate>2017-07-26</actionDate>
        <committee>
          <systemCode>sseg00</systemCode>
          <name>Energy and Natural Resources Committee</name>
        </committee>
        <links />
        <sourceSystem>
          <code>0</code>
          <name>Senate</name>
        </sourceSystem>
        <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources.</text>
        <type>IntroReferral</type>
      </item>
      <item>
        <committee />
        <sourceSystem>
          <code>9</code>
          <name>Library of Congress</name>
        </sourceSystem>
        <actionDate>2017-07-26</actionDate>
        <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
        <links />
        <type>IntroReferral</type>
        <actionCode>10000</actionCode>
      </item>
      <actionByCounts>
        <senate>2</senate>
      </actionByCounts>
      <actionTypeCounts>
        <referredToCommittee>1</referredToCommittee>
        <introducedInSenate>1</introducedInSenate>
      </actionTypeCounts>
    </actions>
    <sponsors>
      <item>
        <bioguideId>W000779</bioguideId>
        <party>D</party>
        <firstName>RON</firstName>
        <middleName />
        <byRequestType />
        <fullName>Sen. Wyden, Ron [D-OR]</fullName>
        <identifiers>
          <lisID>1247</lisID>
          <bioguideId>W000779</bioguideId>
          <gpoId>8265</gpoId>
        </identifiers>
        <lastName>WYDEN</lastName>
        <state>OR</state>
      </item>
    </sponsors>
    <summaries>
      <billSummaries>
        <item>
          <versionCode>00</versionCode>
          <actionDate>2017-07-26</actionDate>
          <updateDate>2017-07-26T04:00:00Z</updateDate>
          <text><![CDATA[<p><b>Recreation Not Red-Tape Act</b></p> <p>This bill amends the Federal Lands Recreation Enhancement Act to require the Bureau of Land Management (BLM) and the Forest Service to review the process for the issuance and renewal of special recreation permits, including for cross-jurisdictional trips, with respect to outfitters and guides. </p> <p>The Department of the Interior and the Department of Agriculture (USDA) shall: (1) coordinate with states to allow the purchase of federal and state recreation passes at federal and state facilities in the same transaction, and (2) sell National Parks and Federal Recreational Lands Passes and entrance and standard amenity recreation fees through federal websites. </p> <p>Interior and USDA should work with the Department of Defense and the Department of Veterans Affairs to ensure that service members and veterans have access to outdoor recreation and to outdoor-related volunteer and wellness programs. </p> <p>The Forest Service, BLM, and National Park Service may develop management plans for extending the recreation season or increasing recreation use during the offseason. </p> <p>The Forest Service and BLM shall evaluate land managers based on the achievement of applicable agency recreational and tourism goals. </p> <p>The Army Corps of Engineers, the Bureau of Reclamation, the Federal Energy Regulatory Commission, and the Department of Transportation shall consider how land and water management decisions can enhance recreation opportunities and the recreation economy. </p> <p>The bill amends the Omnibus Parks and Public Lands Management Act of 1996 to establish the Ski Area Fee Retention Account. A specified portion of rental charges for ski area permits on a Forest Service unit shall be deposited in such account, and a specified portion of such amounts shall be available to such unit for ski area administration, improvements, and visitor services.</p> <p>The bill establishes a National Recreation Area System to be comprised of existing National Recreation Areas and new units designated after enactment of this bill.</p> <p>Interior and USDA shall: (1) develop initiatives to enhance private-sector volunteer programs, actively promote private-sector volunteer opportunities, and provide outreach and coordination to the private sector to carry out projects and programs for the stewardship of federal land; and (2) establish an interagency trail management plan under which federal land management agencies shall coordinate so that trails that cross jurisdictional boundaries between those agencies are uniformly managed and maintained.</p>]]></text>
          <actionDesc>Introduced in Senate</actionDesc>
          <name>Introduced in Senate</name>
          <lastSummaryUpdateDate>2017-12-06T21:31:56Z</lastSummaryUpdateDate>
        </item>
      </billSummaries>
    </summaries>
    <laws />
    <cosponsors>
      <item>
        <fullName>Sen. Ernst, Joni  [R-IA]</fullName>
        <lastName>Ernst</lastName>
        <bioguideId>E000295</bioguideId>
        <isOriginalCosponsor>False</isOriginalCosponsor>
        <middleName />
        <state>IA</state>
        <firstName>Joni</firstName>
        <sponsorshipDate>2017-09-07</sponsorshipDate>
        <sponsorshipWithdrawnDate />
        <party>R</party>
        <identifiers>
          <bioguideId>E000295</bioguideId>
          <lisID>2283</lisID>
          <gpoId />
        </identifiers>
      </item>
      <item>
        <fullName>Sen. Tester, Jon [D-MT]</fullName>
        <lastName>Tester</lastName>
        <bioguideId>T000464</bioguideId>
        <isOriginalCosponsor>False</isOriginalCosponsor>
        <middleName />
        <state>MT</state>
        <firstName>Jon</firstName>
        <sponsorshipDate>2017-12-12</sponsorshipDate>
        <sponsorshipWithdrawnDate />
        <party>D</party>
        <identifiers>
          <bioguideId>T000464</bioguideId>
          <gpoId>8258</gpoId>
          <lisID>1829</lisID>
        </identifiers>
      </item>
    </cosponsors>
  </bill>
  <dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
    <dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
    <dc:language>EN</dc:language>
    <dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
    <dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
    <dc:description>This file contains bill summaries and statuses for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
  </dublinCore>
</billStatus>

