<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<billStatus>
  <bill>
    <policyArea>
      <name>Science, Technology, Communications</name>
    </policyArea>
    <version>1.0.0</version>
    <titles>
      <item>
        <title>Smart Cities and Communities Act of 2017</title>
        <titleType>Short Titles as Introduced</titleType>
        <chamberName />
        <parentTitleType />
        <chamberCode />
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>A bill to promote the use of smart technologies and systems in communities, and for other purposes.</title>
        <titleType>Official Title as Introduced</titleType>
        <chamberName />
        <parentTitleType />
        <chamberCode />
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Smart Cities and Communities Act of 2017</title>
        <titleType>Display Title</titleType>
        <chamberName />
        <parentTitleType />
        <chamberCode />
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Smart Cities and Communities Act of 2017</title>
        <titleType>(Extracted from GPO) Short Titles as Introduced</titleType>
        <chamberName />
        <parentTitleType />
        <chamberCode />
      </item>
    </titles>
    <title>Smart Cities and Communities Act of 2017</title>
    <subjects>
      <billSubjects>
        <policyArea>
          <name>Science, Technology, Communications</name>
        </policyArea>
        <legislativeSubjects />
      </billSubjects>
    </subjects>
    <actions>
      <item>
        <actionDate>2017-10-02</actionDate>
        <committee>
          <systemCode>sscm00</systemCode>
          <name>Commerce, Science, and Transportation Committee</name>
        </committee>
        <links />
        <sourceSystem>
          <code>0</code>
          <name>Senate</name>
        </sourceSystem>
        <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation.</text>
        <type>IntroReferral</type>
      </item>
      <item>
        <actionCode>10000</actionCode>
        <actionDate>2017-10-02</actionDate>
        <committee />
        <links />
        <type>IntroReferral</type>
        <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
        <sourceSystem>
          <code>9</code>
          <name>Library of Congress</name>
        </sourceSystem>
      </item>
      <actionTypeCounts>
        <referredToCommittee>1</referredToCommittee>
        <introducedInSenate>1</introducedInSenate>
      </actionTypeCounts>
      <actionByCounts>
        <senate>2</senate>
      </actionByCounts>
    </actions>
    <cosponsors />
    <laws />
    <sponsors>
      <item>
        <identifiers>
          <lisID>172</lisID>
          <gpoId>8288</gpoId>
          <bioguideId>C000127</bioguideId>
        </identifiers>
        <bioguideId>C000127</bioguideId>
        <lastName>CANTWELL</lastName>
        <fullName>Sen. Cantwell, Maria [D-WA]</fullName>
        <middleName />
        <state>WA</state>
        <party>D</party>
        <firstName>MARIA</firstName>
        <byRequestType />
      </item>
    </sponsors>
    <relatedBills>
      <item>
        <congress>115</congress>
        <number>3895</number>
        <latestAction>
          <actionDate>2017-10-06</actionDate>
          <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Digital Commerce and Consumer Protection.</text>
        </latestAction>
        <latestTitle>Smart Cities and Communities Act of 2017</latestTitle>
        <relationshipDetails>
          <item>
            <type>Identical bill</type>
            <identifiedBy>CRS</identifiedBy>
          </item>
        </relationshipDetails>
        <type>HR</type>
      </item>
      <item>
        <congress>115</congress>
        <number>4151</number>
        <latestAction>
          <actionDate>2017-10-27</actionDate>
          <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Highways and Transit.</text>
        </latestAction>
        <latestTitle>STREET Act</latestTitle>
        <relationshipDetails>
          <item>
            <type>Related bill</type>
            <identifiedBy>CRS</identifiedBy>
          </item>
        </relationshipDetails>
        <type>HR</type>
      </item>
    </relatedBills>
    <amendments />
    <updateDate>2018-02-20T13:04:30Z</updateDate>
    <originChamber>Senate</originChamber>
    <recordedVotes />
    <calendarNumbers />
    <introducedDate>2017-10-02</introducedDate>
    <latestAction>
      <actionDate>2017-10-02</actionDate>
      <links />
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation.</text>
    </latestAction>
    <billNumber>1904</billNumber>
    <notes />
    <createDate>2017-10-03T00:26:18Z</createDate>
    <cboCostEstimates />
    <billType>S</billType>
    <committeeReports />
    <committees>
      <billCommittees>
        <item>
          <chamber>Senate</chamber>
          <systemCode>sscm00</systemCode>
          <name>Commerce, Science, and Transportation Committee</name>
          <subcommittees />
          <type>Standing</type>
          <activities>
            <item>
              <date>2017-10-02T20:37:15Z</date>
              <name>Referred to</name>
            </item>
          </activities>
        </item>
      </billCommittees>
    </committees>
    <congress>115</congress>
    <summaries>
      <billSummaries>
        <item>
          <actionDate>2017-10-02</actionDate>
          <name>Introduced in Senate</name>
          <lastSummaryUpdateDate>2018-02-13T23:11:07Z</lastSummaryUpdateDate>
          <updateDate>2017-10-02T04:00:00Z</updateDate>
          <text><![CDATA[<p><b>Smart Cities and Communities Act of 2017</b></p> <p>This bill directs the Departments of Commerce, Energy, House and Urban Development, and Transportation, the National Science Foundation, and, as appropriate, the Departments of Health and Human Services, Homeland Security, Labor, and State to establish the Interagency Council on Smart Cities to promote coordination of the activities and funding from federal agencies related to smart cities or communities. </p> <p>The council shall develop a multiyear strategy for the coordination of such activities and funding, the development of partnerships with the private sector relating to smart cities or communities, and the promotion of international cooperation with respect to smart city or community technologies and standards. </p> <p>The Department of Labor shall coordinate with private and public organizations and local governments to prepare a smart city or community technology workforce needs assessment.</p> <p>Such departments shall publish a resource guide designed to assist states, communities, and cities in implementing smart city or community programs. </p> <p>Commerce shall:</p> <ul> <li> establish a smart city or community regional demonstration grant program under which demonstration projects on advanced smart city or community technologies and systems shall be conducted in a variety of communities, and </li> <li>convene the Cybersecurity Working Group to develop tools for communities to use to evaluate the cybersecurity of smart city or community technologies. </li> </ul> <p>Labor shall establish the TechHire Workforce Training and Development Pilot Program to furnish competitive grants for technology-based job training and education programs that provide industry-recognized credentials. </p> <p>The Government Accountability Office (GAO) shall conduct a study to identify: (1) financial and procurement mechanisms for funding smart city or community activities and demonstration projects, (2) barriers to creative financing solutions for such activities and projects, and (3) ways to leverage private sector investments in smart cities and communities. </p> <p> The National Institute of Standards and Technology shall support participation by government experts in private sector-led standards-related activities that convene smart city or community stakeholders.</p> <p>Commerce shall establish a strategic international smart cities and communities trade program.</p>]]></text>
          <versionCode>00</versionCode>
          <actionDesc>Introduced in Senate</actionDesc>
        </item>
      </billSummaries>
    </summaries>
  </bill>
  <dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
    <dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
    <dc:language>EN</dc:language>
    <dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
    <dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
    <dc:description>This file contains bill summaries and statuses for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
  </dublinCore>
</billStatus>

