<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<billStatus>
  <bill>
    <sponsors>
      <item>
        <fullName>Sen. Wyden, Ron [D-OR]</fullName>
        <lastName>WYDEN</lastName>
        <bioguideId>W000779</bioguideId>
        <party>D</party>
        <middleName />
        <state>OR</state>
        <firstName>RON</firstName>
        <byRequestType />
        <identifiers>
          <lisID>1247</lisID>
          <bioguideId>W000779</bioguideId>
          <gpoId>8265</gpoId>
        </identifiers>
      </item>
    </sponsors>
    <laws />
    <version>1.0.0</version>
    <introducedDate>2017-08-02</introducedDate>
    <cboCostEstimates />
    <titles>
      <item>
        <chamberName />
        <titleType>Short Titles as Introduced</titleType>
        <title>Southeastern Oregon Development Act</title>
        <parentTitleType />
        <chamberCode />
      </item>
      <item>
        <chamberName />
        <titleType>Official Title as Introduced</titleType>
        <title>A bill to provide for the conduct of certain economic activities in Malheur County, Oregon, to provide for the conduct of a study on the need for a regional economic commission for certain counties in the State of Oregon, to withdraw certain Federal land located in Malheur County, Oregon, from all forms of entry, appropriation, or disposal under the public land laws, location, entry, and patent under the mining laws, and operation under the mineral leasing laws, and for other purposes.</title>
        <parentTitleType />
        <chamberCode />
      </item>
      <item>
        <chamberName />
        <titleType>Display Title</titleType>
        <title>Southeastern Oregon Development Act</title>
        <parentTitleType />
        <chamberCode />
      </item>
      <item>
        <chamberName />
        <titleType>(Extracted from GPO) Short Titles as Introduced</titleType>
        <title>Southeastern Oregon Development Act</title>
        <parentTitleType />
        <chamberCode />
      </item>
    </titles>
    <amendments />
    <recordedVotes />
    <relatedBills />
    <congress>115</congress>
    <billType>S</billType>
    <actions>
      <actionTypeCounts>
        <introducedInSenate>1</introducedInSenate>
        <referredToCommittee>1</referredToCommittee>
      </actionTypeCounts>
      <item>
        <actionDate>2017-08-02</actionDate>
        <committee>
          <systemCode>ssaf00</systemCode>
          <name>Agriculture, Nutrition, and Forestry Committee</name>
        </committee>
        <links />
        <sourceSystem>
          <name>Senate</name>
          <code>0</code>
        </sourceSystem>
        <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Agriculture, Nutrition, and Forestry.</text>
        <type>IntroReferral</type>
      </item>
      <item>
        <type>IntroReferral</type>
        <links />
        <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
        <committee />
        <actionDate>2017-08-02</actionDate>
        <sourceSystem>
          <name>Library of Congress</name>
          <code>9</code>
        </sourceSystem>
        <actionCode>10000</actionCode>
      </item>
      <actionByCounts>
        <senate>2</senate>
      </actionByCounts>
    </actions>
    <notes />
    <originChamber>Senate</originChamber>
    <title>Southeastern Oregon Development Act</title>
    <billNumber>1714</billNumber>
    <cosponsors>
      <item>
        <lastName>Merkley</lastName>
        <sponsorshipDate>2017-08-02</sponsorshipDate>
        <party>D</party>
        <state>OR</state>
        <bioguideId>M001176</bioguideId>
        <middleName />
        <sponsorshipWithdrawnDate />
        <fullName>Sen. Merkley, Jeff [D-OR]</fullName>
        <firstName>Jeff</firstName>
        <isOriginalCosponsor>True</isOriginalCosponsor>
        <identifiers>
          <lisID>1900</lisID>
          <bioguideId>M001176</bioguideId>
          <gpoId>8238</gpoId>
        </identifiers>
      </item>
    </cosponsors>
    <summaries>
      <billSummaries>
        <item>
          <updateDate>2017-08-02T04:00:00Z</updateDate>
          <actionDesc>Introduced in Senate</actionDesc>
          <versionCode>00</versionCode>
          <name>Introduced in Senate</name>
          <text><![CDATA[<p><b>Southeastern Oregon Development Act</b></p> <p>This bill directs the Department of Agriculture (USDA) to make grants for projects in Oregon to develop modern and efficient water systems. </p> <p>USDA shall establish an Agricultural Center for Rangeland Excellence in Malheur County, Oregon (the county).</p> <p>The Farm Security and Rural Investment Act of 2002 is amended to make the rural firefighters and emergency medical service assistance program permanent and require grant amounts to fund the operating expenses of firefighters in rural areas. </p> <p>The Departments of Homeland Security, of Defense, and of the Interior shall establish programs for transferring surplus equipment that can be used in fire fighting.</p> <p>Interior shall establish a program of strategic fuel breaks from which firefighters can operate safely to preserve critical sage grouse habitat and support the nearby ranching community.</p> <p>USDA shall make grants for infrastructure projects for drinking water and wastewater systems and for improvement of broadband or cellular service. </p> <p>The Department of Transportation (DOT) shall study rural air services and infrastructure for Ontario (Oregon) Municipal Airport. </p> <p>DOT shall:</p> <ul> <li>make a grant for the construction or improvement of transportation systems facilitating the efficient movement of agricultural and other products through the Treasure Valley Intermodal Transfer Facility in the county;</li> <li>furnish financial assistance for projects that would improve the downtown area of the cities of the county, surrounding communities, and transportation within the cities; and</li> <li>make grants to the state to support Lake Owyhee road transportation improvement projects. </li> </ul> <p>The Department of Labor shall make grants for workforce development training activities in the county.</p> <p>USDA shall conduct a study on the need for an economic regional commission in specified counties in Oregon. </p> <p>The bill establishes the Southeastern Oregon Withdrawal Area, comprising 2.065 million acres of specified federal land in the county, which shall be withdrawn from certain public land, mining, and mineral leasing laws. </p>]]></text>
          <lastSummaryUpdateDate>2017-11-15T18:50:28Z</lastSummaryUpdateDate>
          <actionDate>2017-08-02</actionDate>
        </item>
      </billSummaries>
    </summaries>
    <policyArea>
      <name>Public Lands and Natural Resources</name>
    </policyArea>
    <latestAction>
      <links />
      <actionDate>2017-08-02</actionDate>
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Agriculture, Nutrition, and Forestry.</text>
    </latestAction>
    <updateDate>2018-02-06T16:45:45Z</updateDate>
    <committees>
      <billCommittees>
        <item>
          <chamber>Senate</chamber>
          <name>Agriculture, Nutrition, and Forestry Committee</name>
          <systemCode>ssaf00</systemCode>
          <activities>
            <item>
              <date>2017-08-02T20:53:17Z</date>
              <name>Referred to</name>
            </item>
          </activities>
          <type>Standing</type>
          <subcommittees />
        </item>
      </billCommittees>
    </committees>
    <createDate>2017-08-03T00:41:45Z</createDate>
    <subjects>
      <billSubjects>
        <policyArea>
          <name>Public Lands and Natural Resources</name>
        </policyArea>
        <legislativeSubjects />
      </billSubjects>
    </subjects>
    <committeeReports />
    <calendarNumbers />
  </bill>
  <dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
    <dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
    <dc:language>EN</dc:language>
    <dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
    <dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
    <dc:description>This file contains bill summaries and statuses for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
  </dublinCore>
</billStatus>

